<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Bminh&#39;s blog</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Bminh&#39;s blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 09:59:59 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
            <title>How this blog was born: the beginning of the nightmare.</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/baivietdautien/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 09:59:59 +0700</pubDate>
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/baivietdautien/</guid>
            <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-this-blog-was-born-the-beginning-is-a-nightmare&#34;&gt;How this blog was born: the beginning is a nightmare.&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hi guys, this is my first post on this blog. I am going to tell you why this whole blog was made and how I created this blog with mistakes I have made.&#xA;Ok now lets get straight into the first part:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-why-this-blog-was-born&#34;&gt;1. Why this blog was born?&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, I simply want to find a place to escape from the distraction of the world. The world is filled with many kinds of entertainment like film, games and the most popular kind of entertainment right now is using social media. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, social media helps people connect to each other, you can learn new things that you accidentally discover.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, people say: &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;The more you get, the less you have&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; and I am the example of that. I joined every social media platform that I know from facebook, instagram, to X. I casually doomscroll on those platforms just to have news, drama and satisfy myself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, what value I have claimed since joining social media? Nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not only I have gained nothing at that time but also it has made my life worse. My downgraded focus made me feel tired and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t focus on one task for a long time. My grade was lower than before and I have to have a retake on three subjects: Calculus, Linear algebra and C language coding, the one that I love the most.&#xA;At that time, I tried to find ways to escape them: deleting plus blocking those apps, doing more work to forget about them. At the end of the day, I still reinstalled those apps and still distracted. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t let my life go on like this, I know that I need to change.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On 13th Feb, 2026, I decided to make this blog help me have a conversation with you guys so that I can trick my brain that: &amp;ldquo;Hey, you are using the best social media, you don&amp;rsquo;t need those distracted platforms anymore&amp;rdquo; (or at least I think so). I hope this blog can be a place that I can relax after a hard time, find back the old me and get better every day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s all, now let&amp;rsquo;s come to the next part, which I call &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;the beginning of the nightmare&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;. Guess how much time I take to make this blog works as a distracted guy? 5 hours. I know it&amp;rsquo;d be better if I can focus on only doing that. But in reality, I can&amp;rsquo;t :).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-creating-a-blog&#34;&gt;2. Creating a blog&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a guy choosing information security/cyber security as a main major, I am not going for writing posts and creating my blogs on WordPress or anything like that because of my sensitivity concerning &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;privacy&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; on those sites. I choose Git with Hugo to do it. Safe, fast and secure-there&amp;rsquo;s no reason I can&amp;rsquo;t refuse.&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s not easy as I think but I am here so I gonna show you how to do it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;installation&#34;&gt;Installation&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I said above, I use Git and Hugo so we need to install both.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hugo&#xA;Install it like a piece of cake. Use this link and install: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/installation/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;Download Hugo&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;It should look like this: &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/baivietdautien/Hugo-install.png&#34;&#xD;&#xA;&#x9;width=&#34;1894&#34;&#xD;&#xA;&#x9;height=&#34;985&#34;&#xD;&#xA;&#x9;loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&#xD;&#xA;&#x9;&#xD;&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;alt=&#34;Hugo’s official site&#34;&#xD;&#xA;&#x9;&#xD;&#xA;&#x9;&#xD;&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; &#xD;&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;data-flex-grow=&#34;192&#34;&#xD;&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;data-flex-basis=&#34;461px&#34;&#xD;&#xA;&#x9;&#xD;&#xA;&gt;&#xA;Install version depends on your OS.&#xA;If you are a cool guy, don&amp;rsquo;t click that link, just do this:&#xA;&lt;code&gt;winget install Hugo.Hugo.Extended&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Git&#xA;Same as Hugo, click this to install:&#xA;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/install/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&#xD;&#xA;    &gt;Download Git&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;It should look like this: &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/baivietdautien/Git-install.png&#34;&#xD;&#xA;&#x9;width=&#34;1920&#34;&#xD;&#xA;&#x9;height=&#34;984&#34;&#xD;&#xA;&#x9;loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&#xD;&#xA;&#x9;&#xD;&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;alt=&#34;Git’s official site&#34;&#xD;&#xA;&#x9;&#xD;&#xA;&#x9;&#xD;&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; &#xD;&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;data-flex-grow=&#34;195&#34;&#xD;&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;data-flex-basis=&#34;468px&#34;&#xD;&#xA;&#x9;&#xD;&#xA;&gt;&#xA;For those who still want to be cool:&#xA;&lt;code&gt;winget install Git.Git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you use that code and you see the download took so long, you&amp;rsquo;re not alone. I have the same issue with that.&#xA;There are many reasons for that problem: Downloaded from different servers, cache/Ram problem, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You still wait and see Git&amp;rsquo;s still downloading? Just &lt;code&gt;Ctrl C&lt;/code&gt; and type &lt;code&gt;winget install Git.Git --interactive&lt;/code&gt; to see what&amp;rsquo;s the problem in order to fix it.&#xA;If you still can&amp;rsquo;t fix it? Well then stop acting cool and hit the link to download.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it. I know many people gonna ask:&#xA;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Where&amp;rsquo;s the nightmare, are you clickbait or something?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post is already long enough (I even feel a bit lazy to read my own post to check mistakes lol) so the nightmare&amp;rsquo;s on the next post after this one, be ready for that!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
        </item></channel>
</rss>
